Welcome brothers and sisters to another
Wednesday question and answer where we
open up with the ten commandments that
God commanded the whole world to keep.
Brother Tenzel,
and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which had brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the
iniquities of the fathers upon the
children, and to the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me, and
showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guilt that take of his name in
vain. Remember the Sabbath day to keep
it holy. Six days shall thou labor and
do all thy work. But the seventh day is
the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it
thou shalt not do any work. Thou nor thy
son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in the midst, and rested the seventh
day. When for the Lord blessed the
Sabbath day, and hallowed it. Honor thy
father and thy mother, that thy days may
be long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shall not kill.
Thou shall not commit adultery. Thou
shall not steal. Thou sh not bear false
witness against thy neighbor. Thou sh
not cover thy neighbor's house. Thou
must not cover thy neighbor's wife, nor
his man's servant, nor his maid servant,
nor his ox, nor his ass, nor anything
that is thy neighbor. We read Exodus
21-17. And may the Lord have a blessing
to the reading of his words. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen. Amen. Amen. So here
on question and answer, you can ask us a
question and we'll answer it according
to the King James Bible. And if we
cannot find the answer, we will seek
further counsel to bring you an answer
at a later time. The questions we will
not answer are the vague and long
scripture questions as well as questions
of debate. We are not here to debate. We
are here to spread the true gospel of
Jesus. So please be as direct as
possible with your questions so we can
be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or book will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream and
you may begin to send in your questions
at this time. Even questions that
pertain to everlasting life, we just
asking that you keep them to a two
scripture maximum. But let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. Brother Dre, good evening.
Brother Jerome, grace in peace. Brother
Julius, good evening everybody. Brother
Tanzel, good evening. Sister Deborah,
good evening.
Brother Sean,
good evening. And we have the guest
caller with us. And I'm brother Cornell.
Sister, what is our first question of
the evening?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's
Q&A. Me too for you. Jones asks in Titus
verse14, what are Jewish fables and the
actual word Jewish? Is this particular
word anywhere else in the Bible?
All right, brother Dre. We know it's a
lot of fables out here. What you say,
brother? Yeah, Jewish fables are untrue
spoken
by Jews. But it's only written in the
Bible one time. So that word Jewish is
only written once here. But let's go to
Titus 1 and read verse 14. When you get
it, Tanzel, go ahead.
not giving heed to Jewish fables and
commandments of men that turn from the
truth. Now notice it said these are
these fables are the commandments of men
and they turn from the truth. Let's go
look at that. Let's go to Matthew 15 and
we going to start at verse one there.
Matthew 15 and1.
Matthew 15 and1. Yes sir. Then came to
Jesus scribes and Pharisees which were
of Jerusalem,
saying, "Why do thy disciples transgress
the tradition of the elders? For they
wash not their hands when they eat
bread,
but they but he answered and said unto
them, but why did he also transgress the
commandments of God by your tradition?"
So you transgressing the commandments of
God by your
tradition. Jesus is talking to these
Pharisees. Look at what he says. Skip
down to verse seven. Go ahead. You
hypocrites. Well, as I prophesied of
you, saying, "This people draw nigh unto
me with their mouth and honor me with
their lips, but their heart is far from
me. But in vain they do worship me,
teaching for doctrines the commandments
of men."
See, then that is what's happening here.
So when you read Titus, it says, "Not
giving heed to Jewish fables and
commandments of men that turn from the
truth." And then Jesus speaking to these
Pharisees and they are giving things
that are commandments of men and not the
commandments of God. Right. But it's
only mentioned one time in the
Bible, the word
is. Other than that, it's nowhere else
in the Bible. That's all I got.
That's right, brother. Teaching the
doctrines and commandments of men cannot
profit you. That's right, brother. All
right. Thank you for that, brother. Hope
that answered their question. As we move
on to our next moving on Norless T asks
in Ezekiel 13 vers 17 through
21 pillow scenes pillows sewn to
armholes Kchief placed on heads for the
purpose of hunting souls to make them
fly. What is Ezekiel talking about?
All right, brother Julius, shed some
light on what Ezekiel talking about.
Looks like they gave the scriptures
Ezekiel the 13th chapter. Let's go
there, Tenzel verses 17-
21. But what we going to do, we going to
start at Ezekiel 13 and 1 to find the
foundation of of what Ezekiel is talking
about. Pick it up at verse one. Ezekiel
13 1 to3 quickly. Go ahead, brother. And
the word of the Lord came unto me,
saying, Son of man, prophesy against the
prophets of Israel, that prophesies and
say thou unto them that prophesies out
of their own hearts. Hear ye the word of
the Lord. Uhhuh. Thus sayeth the Lord
God, but woe unto the foolish prophets
that follow their own spirit and have
seen nothing. Verse six, please. They
have seen vanity and lying devation
saying the Lord said and the Lord have
not sent them and they have made others
to hope that they would confirm the
word. So now this is talking about the
foundation of the scripture is talking
about false prophets that prophesy uh
lies out of their own mouths out of
their own imagination of their minds and
not out of the mouth of the Lord. So
what happened was the women got caught
up into this. Skip down to verse 17 and
go ahead.
Likewise, thou, son of man, set thy face
against the daughters of thy people,
which prophesies out of their own heart,
and prophesize thou against them. So
now, now the women are becoming false
prophets and uh uh following pagan
deities such as uh Ishtar, uh Esther, uh
Baalism and so on. Uh go ahead. and say,
"Thus said the Lord God, reward to the
woman that sow pillows to all armholes
and make curt handkerchiefs upon the
heads of every statue to hunt souls."
Uhhuh. "Will you hunt the souls of my
people? And will ye save the souls alive
that come unto you?" Yes.
And would you pollute me among my people
for handfuls of barley and for pieces of
bread to slay the souls that should not
die and to save the souls alive that
should not live by your lying to my
people that hear your lies. So now at
that verse 18 your question is what is
you talking about with these with the
women that sold pillars to arms and make
certifie? Kurtise is a short word for
handkerchieese, right? Okay. The
throwing the pillows to the armholes is
the padding that they add to their
garments. Like you see a man that's got
a suit but his but it's padded to make
his shoulders look broad. Where the
women had these things on their garments
also paddings puff that make them puffed
up. You could in the Elizabethanian age,
you see these garments at the um uh in
the olden days that they want to make
their shoulders look big and puffed up.
These are their dresses that they wear
or their garments. And they would
deceive people by their looks. Like you
see a man dressed up with the priest
collar, he looks like he's from God, but
it's deception. Right? You see the h our
people now you see uh the false prophets
they are selling you tap water to
deceive you. They are selling you
handkerchiefs, prayer cloths. That's
deception. They are drawing you away
from God. Now they're waving towels and
people are falling all out and they're
waving jackets and people are falling
all out. So that's what this whole thing
is talking about. You are hunting souls
and you are taking them away from God by
your deception. And so therefore, uh, it
shall not profit. And the Lord say he is
against that.
That's all I got on that.
Hey, can I make a comment? Yes, sir.
Yeah. You know, uh, it was a while when
Paul was healing people. Yes. And maybe
somebody could find it. Even they had
handkerchief that that, uh, that that
come from Paul. Yes.
They could use them handkerchiefs and
say and and it would heal people. Can
somebody find that right quick? I'm just
showing you where some of this came
from. Yes. All right. We in search mode
now.
Like the lady told me, uh Jesus touched
him her garment, she was healed. Uh it
was her faith that healed her.
Yeah. Well, she believed that uh it
would but the whole thing is Paul was
healing people and they say even
handkerchief from Paul body. Yes.
Was healing people. Let's go to Acts
chapter. Let's see if that's it. What?
Acts
19 out and see.
Acts 19.
Let me see here. 12-
16. Acts 19 and 12. Kenzia picking up at
verse 11.
And God brought special miracles by the
hand of Paul, so that from his body were
brought unto the sick handkerchiefs or
aprons, and the disease departed from
them, and the evil spirits went out of
them.
Yes. And that's guess called saying that
that's the origin of that. You're right.
That's where all that that's where it
come from. You know, like in the old
days, they used to they used to
advertise, you know, on TV, you know.
some of these preachers, you know, we we
would send you a handkerchief and this
would heal you all and they and they got
it from Paul. So that's what Ezekiel is
to a lot of that part of that. That's
all I want to say. Thank you. Yes, sir.
Sound like those handkerchiefs are good
for blowing your nose only. All right.
We hope that that answered your question
there as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Marian Lewis asks, "If one is
baptized at Israel, the church of Jesus,
and begins to attend the Israel of God,
does one have to be baptized again under
iog."
But if you've been
baptized in Jesus' name, under the one
that died for the sins of the whole
world, then no, there will be no need
for you to get rebaptized again.
And that's all I got on
that. And we hope that that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. Next one. Jennifer Love
asks, "A person that has not been
baptized cannot take the Passover. Is
this correct?"
Nope. That's not correct. You don't have
to be baptized to partake in the
Passover. But however, you do have to be
circumcised to partake in the
Passover. So, let's go to um let's go to
1 Corinthians 5 and 7. Let's see who who
the Passover is
first.
Because when we find out who it is that
is the
Passover, keep in mind that he was also
circumcised at 8 days old. He gave the
law and he kept the law when he came in
the flesh. 1 Corinthians 5 and 7. When
you get there, brother, go
ahead. Purge out therefore the old
leaven that ye may be a new lump as ye
are unleavened. For even Christ our
Passover is sacrificed for us. All
right. So Christ our
Passover was sacrificed for us. He is a
Passover. He died for the sins of the
whole world, even for the children that
had not been born. But let's go back to
Exodus 12. Exodus the 12th
chapter. And when you get there, let's
read that verse 43 and 44. And deal a
little bit more with the Passover here
because the Lord that gave the Passover,
he's going to speak to Moses and Aaron
right here. Go ahead.
And the Lord said unto Moses and Aaron,
"This is the ordinance of the Passover,
there should no stranger eat
thereof, man servant that is bought for
money. When thou hast circumcised him,
then shall he eat thereof." Oh, so you
have to be circumcised in order to
partake in the Passover. And this is
what the Lord was telling Moses and
Aaron here. Skip down to verse 47 cuz
the Lord wanted all of Israel to keep
that because those are the ones that he
chose to teach the rest of the world. Go
ahead. All the congregation of Israel
shall keep it. And when a stranger shall
adjourn with thee, and we'll keep the
Passover to the Lord, let all his males
be
circumcised. And then let them come near
and keep it and he shall be as one that
is born in the land. For no
uncircumcised person shall eat thereof.
So if you uncircumcised, you cannot
partake of the Passover. And the Lord
was saying, even for the stranger, the
people that may so join with us in order
to keep the Passover and to hear about
this great God, if they want to partake
in the Passover, they had to also be
circumcised. It was one law for all.
Read that next uh 49 for me.
One law shall be to him that is
homeborn, and unto the stranger that's
ajour among you. Uhhuh. So read that 50
and that'll be it. Thus did all the
children of Israel as the Lord commanded
Moses and Aaron. So did they. So yeah,
you don't have to be baptized, but you
do have to be circumcised.
And hopefully you will put a baptism in
your future because the Lord require
that also when you are ready to come
under the blood of Jesus. And that's all
I got. Right.
And we hope that that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Valencia asks, "Can you tell
me what is a teal tree? Isaiah 6 verse3
is given." And brother Dre, share with
us about what is a teal tree. Let's go
read that. Isaiah 6 and13. When you get
it, Tanzel, go ahead.
But yet in it shall be a tent, and it
shall return, and shall be eaten as a
teal tree, and as an oak, whose
substance is in them, and when they cast
their leaves, so the holy seed shall be
the substance thereof.
Right? So, a teal tree is, as I looked
it up, it it talked about it being a
lime tree, the tilla, the terabith, the
tarpentine tree, the pistachio tree, and
these are what botonists call this this
tree. So, it is it's in the family of
those.
Um the significance of it I guess if a
tree is cut down what will it bring
forth? But the question that you ask is
what is a teal tree? And when you look
up what a teal tree is there's uh
there's a number of of trees that are
named which would probably be in the
family of a teal tree. But but the
significance is another thing.
And uh I just want to touch on it since
we here. Let's go to Job 14. Job 14 and
we're going to read verses 7
to9. Job 14
7-9. Go ahead when you get it, brother.
For there is hope of a tree, if it be
cut down, that it will sprout again, and
that the tender branch thereof will not
cease.
Though the root thereof waxs old in the
earth, and the stock thereof die in the
ground, but yet through the scent of
water, it will bud and bring forth boss
like a plant.
So the Lord is talking
about as as we being trees, he will
bring us forth out of
those there will be a substance of those
that will come forth out of the
leaves. And so he goes on in this job
and asks the question, if a man die, he
gonna live again. Of course he will.
It's just where he chooses to live at
and how he lives now. So, I hope that
helps. But the the teal tree itself has
several different trees that are
mentioned within that family. Yeah, Dre,
I also looked it up also and uh uh it's
the blossom of the oak tree is the acorn
and the blossom of the teal tree is
similar to the pistachio. Yes, sir. Yes,
sir.
All right, thank you all for that. I
hope that answered your question as we
continue to move right along. Moving
along, Stephen Gooas asked in Isaiah 13
verse14, "Is this going to happen during
the time tribulation? Will all that is
in Israel go to their own country during
the time of tribulation or join Israel
in the wilderness?
All right. Why don't we go to that
Isaiah
13 and pick it up at that verseh 14 and
then the guest caller will share some
light from there.
Isaiah 13 and 14. Yep. And it shall be
as the chase ro and as a sheep that no
man taketh up. I say every man turn to
his own people that flee everyone into
his own land.
Okay, that's uh it says what it says.
Everybody going to turn to their own
people and flee to their own land. But
just like it was when Israel left Egypt
and went into the ill wilderness, there
was also other people from other
nationalities that went with them
because the book said it was a mixed
multitude. So it's going to be the same.
They going to go and you're going to get
some strangers that's going to go into
the
wilderness with Israel. And when they
come out of the wilderness, they going
to go into the land of Israel and they
going to be among the nation of be a
part of the nation of
Israel. Let's go into Ezekiel the 47th
chapter and read verses 21- 23.
that Ezekiel 47
chapter verses 21- 23.
So shall ye divide this land unto you
according to the tribes of Israel. And
it shall come to pass that ye shall
divide it by lot for inheritance unto
you, and to the stranger that's
adjourneth among you, which shall begat
children among you, and they shall be
unto you as born in the country among
the children of Israel, and they shall
have inheritance with you among the
tribes of Israel. It shall come to pass
that in what tribe the strangest
adjourneth, there shall ye give him his
inheritance, sayeth the Lord God.
So now and it was the same thing in the
beginning. So overall everybody's going
to turn to their own people and they
going to go to their own country. God is
going to set the order the earth back up
in the order that he wanted it. But as
in the days of old, you going to always
have some some strangers that want to
stay among the Israelites.
For sure some strangers going to go
through the
wilderness and they going to continue on
to the land. But overall only
Israel as the whole nation will go to
the wilderness. That's all I have to
say. All
right. Hope that answered your question
as we continue to move to our next
question. Next question. Black Mold
asks, "Are
Ham Gentiles also?" "Are Ham Gentiles
also?"
All right, brother Jerome. Are Ham
Gentiles?
Uh, absolutely not. Uh, only the sons of
Gentiles. So, let's go to that Gen
Genesis the 10th chapter and take a look
at it.
Genesis 10, pick it up at two. Read it
to the
file. The sons of
and Madiah and Jan and Tubald and
Meek and Tyrus and the sons of GMA,
Ashenaz and Rimhav and Togamar. And the
sons of Javan, Alissia and Tarses, Kdum
and Dudenim. By these were the hours of
the Gentiles divided in their land,
everyone after his tongue, after the
families in their
nations. You the people we uh commonly
call white people, Europeans. Okay. Th
those are the sons of Jay Fat, not Ham.
Ham are the are people that we refer to
as Africans
today. That's all I got on.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
I hope that answered their question as
we move on. Moving on. Me too for you.
Jones asks, "Did Adam and Eve see Jesus
in his fullness or did they ever see him
at all?" Also, will they inherit eternal
life?
All right, we know they saw Jesus. Guess
caller.
Well, we assume that they saw Jesus.
But I'm pretty sure he wasn't in his
full strength. However, I know one thing
for sure. He was there with them. Go
into Genesis the 3r chapter and read
8-10. Genesis 3 picking up at verse
8. And they heard the voice of the Lord
God walking in the garden in the cool of
the day. Adam and his wife head
themselves from the presence of the Lord
God amongst the trees of the garden. And
the Lord God called unto Adam and said
unto him, Where art thou? And he said, I
heard thy voice in the garden, and I was
afraid because I was naked and I hid
myself.
So that mean that
uh if you going to hide yourself, that
mean that you was around him, right?
Most likely. and most likely saw him.
But in his full
strength, that wouldn't happen because
look what happened to Moses when he hung
around God for 40 days. He start he
start to uh take on the characteristic
of a spirit being. He started to shine.
There's no evidence. Adam and Eve as far
as uh uh them get eternal life.
Everybody that's ever been born is going
to get eternal life.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question. As we move on to
our next one with a time check. Yes, the
time is 7:59.
Glenn Sirius asks, "Are the 70 years
mentioned in 2 Chronicles
36 19- 21 related to the 70 years in
Daniel
9:es 2- 24? If so, how are they
related?"
All right, they're talking about the 70
years and the relation here and it
starts off with that question in 2
Chronicles
36 and pick it up at verse 19 and the
guest column would take it from
there. And they burned the house of God
and break down the walls of Jerusalem
and burn all the palaces thereof with
fire and destroy all the goodly vessels
thereof.
You said 2 Chronicles 36, right? That's
correct. You're in the right place. And
then thy head escaped from the sword,
carry he away to Babylon, where they
were servants to him and his sons until
the reign of the kingdom of Persia to
fulfill the word of the Lord by the
mouth of Jeremiah to the land had
enjoyed her Sabbath. For as long as she
laid desolate, she kept Sabbath to
fulfill three score in 10 years.
So, so the whole Yeah. Yes. Both of them
are talking about the same
time.
Physically, Israel was returned 70
years, but that turned into the 70
weeks, which still we haven't gotten to
the end of it. But to let you know, they
was talking about the same time. Both of
them referred to Jeremiah's
uh uh uh prophecy. Read V Daniels 9
and2.
In the first year of his reign, I doubt
you understood by books the number of
the years where the word of the Lord
came to Jeremiah the prophet that he
would accomplish 70 years in the
desolation of Jerusalem.
It says the word of the Lord that came
uh by Jeremiah the prophet. Now let's go
into 2 Chronicle 36 and read verse 21.
to fulfill the word of the Lord by the
mouth of Jeremiah unto the land had
enjoyed her Sabbath. For as long as she
lay desolate, she kept Sabbath to
fulfill three score in 10 years.
So that's talking about both of them are
talking about the same time and that
goes beyond 70 literal years. Let's go
within a time that's called the 70 weeks
of Daniel's. And that will not be over
with until the Lord come. That's all I
have to say.
You muted, Carell. Thank you for that.
Hope that answers your question. As we
move on to our next next one, Jalia
says, "There are trans transgenders on
my job. My Lee says, "I have to identify
them as females. I refuse but choose to
call them by the name on their name
tag." Are there any supporting
scriptures or am I wrong?
Brother Julius, what you say? until they
change their names on their name tags to
what they want to be called. I will call
them by what their name tags identify
them as. Now, your lead has a lead over
him, which is management. I don't know
if you could find out what their what
their names is in the in the U because
the name tag is supposed to be an
official h item of
identification. So although you got to
do your job, you know, and it's a tough
situation,
um, until they change their name to
reflect what they want to be called, I
have to go by the name what's on the
name tag and check that out with the
office. What is the official name? Uh,
in the office. That's the best I can do
with that. I hope that helped.
All right, that's a good answer. Calling
by the name is only to
All
right, we're going to move on to our
next question.
The other part of that, are there any
scriptures? Romans 12 and 18. As much as
lith in you, live peacefully with one
another. Still got to do your
job. All right.
Sister Deborah, we moving on to our next
next one. Ka
Oan Amy asks, "What will be the reason
for animal sacrifice in Jesus kingdom?
And will it be for an offering or a
peace offering?"
All right, brother Jerome, we talking
about the animal sacrifice in Jesus'
kingdom.
Yeah. Um, the Lord made a a a covenant
uh of salt with the with the Levites and
he got to bring back animal sacrifices
uh in order to keep that covenant
assault um with the Levites and with the
sons of Aaron. Okay. So, let's go to
Numbers the 18th chapter and we're going
to pick it up at verse 8 and read it to
the 13. We going to skip
numbers 18 and 8. Yeah.
And the Lord spake to Aaron, behold, I
also have given thee the charge of my
heave offering of all the hollow things
of the children of Israel. Unto thee
have I given them by reasoning of the
anointing, and to thy sons by ordinance
forever.
Read it to the 13.
And this shall be thine of the most holy
things reserved from the fire. Every
oblation of theirs, every meat offering
of theirs, and every sin offering of
theirs, and every trespass offering of
theirs, which they shall render unto me
shall be most holy for thee, and for thy
sons. And the most holy place shall thou
eat it. Every male shall eat it. It
shall be holy unto thee. And this is
thine, the heave offering of their gift
with all the wave offering of the
children of Israel. I have given them
unto thee to thy sons and to thy
daughters with thee by statue forever.
Everyone that is clean, and thy house
shall eat of it. All the best of the
ore, and all the best of the wine, and
all the wheat of the first fruits of
them which they shall offer unto the
Lord, them have I given thee. And
whatsoever is first ripe in the land,
which they shall bring unto the Lord,
shall be thine. Everyone that is clean
in thy house shall eat of it. Okay, now
let's uh go right into uh verse 19. Skip
down to verse 19 and read it to 21.
All the heave offerings of the holy
things which the children of Israel
offer unto the Lord have I given thee
and thy sold sons and thy daughters with
thee by statute forever. It is a
covenant of Saul forever before the Lord
unto thee and to thy seed with thee. And
the Lord spake unto Aaron, Thou shalt
have no inheritance in the land, neither
shalt thou have any part among them. I
am thy part, and thy inheritance among
the children of Israel. And behold, I
have given the children of Levi all the
10th in Israel for an inheritance, for
their service, which they serve, even
the service of the tabernacle of the
congregation.
That's all I got on.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Jay Tadvo
says, "Could it be in Leviticus 19
27 where it prohibits certain hair and
beer practices that were associated with
pagan morning rituals intended to
distinguish God's people from such
practices?"
All right. Looks like that question
starts off in Leviticus 19 and 27.
When you get there, go ahead, brother.
And the guest caller will take it from
there.
You should not round the corners of your
head. Neither shall thou mar the corners
of thy beard.
Keep going. The question
is, question is, could it be because of
some pagan hair
do?
No. Like I said before, we don't
know. At the Israeli God, we don't
interpret. We read what the Lord said
is. And if he wanted us to know exactly
what if he want us wanted if it was
wanted us to stop wearing something
pagan hair do then he would have written
it. So like I said the last
time I don't
know it's obvious that you don't either.
That's all I have to say. All right
we'll leave it there and we're gonna
keep moving on to our next question.
Next question. Straight Talk says, "I
hear my name whispered to me, but no one
is calling me. Can you help me with
this?"
All right. So, they're saying that they
hear their name whispered to them, but
no one is calling them, and they would
like a little light on that. Let's open
it up for the panels.
He said, "Can you help me with it?" The
question is
no. But I'll give you an example where
it did happen and it might be happening
to you. Only thing we can do is give you
an example was written in the
book. And let's go into 1st Samuel 3
chapter and read from 1 to 11. Verses
1-1.
1 Samuel 3.
Yeah, start reading at verse one and
read through 11.
And the child Samuel ministered unto the
Lord before Eli. And the word of the
Lord was precious in those days. There
was no open vision. And it came to pass
at that time when Eli was laid down in
his place, and his eyes began to wax dim
that he could not see. And ear the lamp
of God went out in the temple of the
Lord, where the ark of God was. And
Samuel was laid down to
sleep. Then the Lord called Samuel, and
he answered, "Here am I." And he ran
unto Eli and said, "Here am I, for thou
callest me." And he said, I call him
not. Lie down again. And he went and
laid him
down. And the Lord called yet again,
Samuel. And Samuel rose and went to Eli
and said, Well, here am I, for thou
didest call me. And he answered, "When I
called not, my son, lie down again." Now
Samuel did not yet know the Lord,
neither was a word of the Lord yet
revealed unto him. And the Lord called
Samuel again the third time. And he
arose and went to Eli and said, "Here am
I, but thou didest call me." And Eli
perceived that the Lord had called the
child. So therefore Eli said unto
Samuel, "Well, go lie down, and it shall
be if he call thee, and thou shalt say,
speak, Lord, for thy servant heareth."
So Samuel went down, went and laid down
in this place. And the Lord came and
stood and called as at other times,
Samuel, Samuel. Then Samuel answered,
"Speak, for thy servant heareth." And
the Lord said to Samuel, "Behold, I will
do a thing in Israel at which both the
ears of everyone that heareth it shall
tingle."
So maybe you should take the advice that
Eli gave Samuel. If you hear a voice
calling your name, then maybe you should
uh say the same thing that Eli advised
Samuel and Samuel did. That's about all
I can give you on that.
All right.
Hope that will be of assistance to you.
Let's move on to our next question. Next
question. Nice tape says, "Wouldn't
Jesus have just abolished ended death
and hell? Why did he cast them in the
lake of fire to punish them with the
rest of the sinners? He is going to
punish them forever. Only living beings
sin.
Brother
Julius, what you say? I see something
that you added
here. You added that he's going to uh uh
punish death and hell. Let's look at
what the books say. Let's go to
Revelation and read your scriptures.
Let's go to Revelation the 20th chapter,
brother Tanzel, and let's see if it says
that he going to punish death and hell.
Death and hell is a state of
condition. The death means absence of
life and hell in this context is the
grave. Read verse 13.
And the sea gave up the dead which were
in it, and death and hell delivered up
the dead which were in them. That's the
great
Go ahead. Judge every man according to
their works.
Go ahead. And death and hell were cast
into the lake of fire to punish them.
Did it say that?
It just said death and hell, that is the
grave. Everything that God terminates or
don't need anymore goes into the lake of
fire. Finish it. This is the second
death. Now it said death and hell. Let's
go to Psalms. Psalms is 16th
chapter. Look what look what the prophet
David cuz he said the spirit of the Lord
spoke by him concerning
Jesus. Verse 9, 9 and 10. When you get
it, go ahead. Therefore my heart is glad
and my glory rejoicing. My flesh go
ahead.
My flesh also shall rest in hope. You
rest in the grave. That is but that's
why you say RIP. Rest in peace. Go
ahead. But you're in the grave. You're
resting. You sleep. You're dead. Uh go
ahead.
For I will not leave my soul in hell.
You're not going to leave my body in the
grave. Go ahead. Neither without suffer
thy holy one to see corruption. Jesus
did not see corruption. He was in the
grave three days and three nights and
rose. He did not see corruption. So let
us show you, let me show you what the
condition of death and hell is. Let's go
to Ecclesiastes the 9th chapter.
Ecclesiastes
9. And we're going to pick this up, my
brother, at verse we going to start at
verse
10. Ecclesiastes
9, pick it up at verse 5.
Let's see. When you are alive, you are a
living being. You have you have
consciousness, awareness. But go ahead.
For the living know that they shall die,
but the dead know not anything. That's a
condition. You don't know nothing. Go
ahead. Neither have they anymore a
reward. For the me memory of them is
forgotten. They don't have no memory in
the grave. Go ahead.
Also their love and their hatred and
their envy is now perished. Neither have
they any more a portion forever in
anything that is done under the sun.
Because the dead know not, nor aware, no
consciousness. Verse 10.
Whatsoever thy hand findest to do, do it
with thy might. For there is no work,
nor device, nor knowledge, nor wisdom in
the grave whether thou goest. And that
is a condition lifeless absence of life.
You are dead. You are asleep until a
resurrection. So it sounds like to being
this question which is bleded over to
this week from last week that you are
trying to make death and hell evil
angels and they are not. They are uh it
is a state of condition. That's the best
I can do with that. Cornell.
Yeah. You know, you know, he said what
Jesus said, you brought up my soul from
hell. Didn't he read that? Yeah. Yep.
When that same in Psalms also which
talks about you brought up my soul from
the grave and somebody read
that. I think that's Psalms
30. Say Psalms 30, brother. Yeah, I
think that's Psalms 30.
if you can find and read it. Oh yeah.
Verse three 30. Yeah, right on point
there. 303.
Oh Lord, thou hast brought up my soul
from the grave. Thou hast kept me alive
that I should not go down to the pit.
Okay. But the other place he say brought
up his soul from hell, didn't it? Right.
M.
So now
death, you have to die to go to grave.
And and this hell is talking about is
talking about the grave. But I like to
ask the question, how is it that a
couple of angels had Jesus inside of
them and he had to be risen up out of
them? Impossible. That don't make sense.
Impossible.
Okay. I just said, "Look at He said, you
know, and and and uh and death and hell
gave up the dead that was in there." You
mean them angels had all a bunch of dead
people inside of them?
Come on. And I think I think that's
Psalms 86 and 13 too might be what you
hitting on. Psalm 86 and 13.
Read it. Go ahead. 13.
For great is thy mercy toward me, and
thou has delivered up my soul from the
lowest hill.
Okay.
So, uh,
of condition,
huh?
He terminated. That's all this is
saying. He terminated death. Don't need
it no more. Don't need the grave no
more. That's it. Cuz if because if
everybody going to be immortal then why
should you
die and you don't die rather so you
don't buried living people right
only bury dead.
Okay. All right. That was some good
light shed there. We hope that answered
your question. Sister Deborah, are we
taking a trip into new territory? Uh
yes. We are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, March the 19,
2025. Harold Bird Long
asks, "In Revelations 3:es
1-4, are these verses in Turkey in the
latter days or am I missing the mark?"
Brother Julius, are they missing the
mark? Uh, yeah.
Yeah, you're missing the mark. These
these churches are located in what's
called Turkey or Asia Minor, our modern
day Turkey. And let's go to Revelation
the first
chapter. Let's go to first Revelation
the first chapter because
John the is a prophecy. This is a
prophecy to the to the seven churches,
but it's end time
prophecy that's going to take place
mostly in Jerusalem and around the world
in different different areas, not just
Turkey. And pick it up at verse uh look
what John said. Verse pick it up at
verse 9. Go ahead, Tenzel. I John who
also am your brother and companion in
tribulation and in the kingdom and
patience of Jesus Christ was in the ales
that is called Patmos for the word of
God and for the testimony of Jesus
Christ. The island of Patmos belongs to
Greece but is 38 miles from the coast of
Turkey. Continue.
I was in the spirit on the Lord's day
and heard behind me a great voice as of
a
trumpet, saying, I am Alpha and Omega,
the first and the last. And what thou
seeest right in the book, and send it
unto the seven churches which are in
Asia, in Ephesus, and into Smyrna, and
into Pergamos, and into Thyra, and into
Sardis, and into Philadelphia, and into
Ladosia. Now these were the modern
churches uh of the what they call the
apostolic age. Uh and a lot of this is
fulfilled because it mentions if you
read about the to each church an angel
was assigned
and it deals with uh things that were
going on then and things that are yet uh
to happen. So it's a it's a dispensation
of time.
Your scripture is in Revelation 3 and 4.
That's why it says at verse one about to
the church in Sardis, right? You know,
so this is uh the things that were going
on in that time and at that
day. So, but we know that the main
prophecy is going to be on the European
and African continents and in the Middle
East because that's where has always
been and that's where it's going to
stay. Anybody want to add to that?
Yeah. And most and most of this is
future prophecy that they give you a
good example. What does it say in
Revelation 2:9 and 3:9? Yeah,
I know thy works.
I know thy works in tribulation,
poverty, for thou are rich, and I know
the blasphemy of them which say that
they are Jews and are not, but are the
synagogues of Satan. Mhm.
Now, now and read.
Behold, I will make them of the
synagogue of Satan, which say they are
Jews, and are not, but do lie. Behold, I
will make them to come and worship
before thy feet, and to know that I have
loved thee. Yes.
Look, so all of this is people that call
themselves Jews and are not. All that
happened after 70 AD. Yeah.
John wrote to Revelation. Everybody knew
who Israel was. Everybody knew who the
Jew was. So could nobody come in and say
that we are the
Jews. But they li but they were but they
was not. So most of this is talking
about future. It's just like the church
of
Leia. That's the Catholic church. Yes.
So this mostly God used these uh uh like
writing a letter to these churches but
the prophecies are end time prophecies.
Yes.
Because at that time you had no people
running around saying we are the Jew and
they was not. They was called by the
name Esau or Adumians.
That's all I have to say. All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one. Moving on.
Newless tape says, "Were the 144,000
wearing white robes not saved before the
end coming of Jesus?"
All right. Guess call about the 144,000.
Well, no. you know, uh uh
they were
sealed. Let's go and and and uh uh uh
read
that in in Revelation the 7th
chapter and show you that uh the Lord
held everything up until he sealed this
144,000. We start at verse one and read
to the 144,000.
And after these things I saw four angels
standing on the four corners of the
earth, holding the four winds of the
earth, that the wind should not blow on
the earth, nor on the sea, nor on any
tree. And I saw another angel ascending
from the east, having the seal of the
living God. And he cried with a loud
voice to the four angels, to whom it was
given to hurt the earth and the sea,
saying, Hurt not the earth, neither the
sea, nor the trees, till we have sealed
the servants of our God, and therefore
his. And I heard the number of them
which were sealed. And there were sealed
140 and 4,000s of all the tribes of the
children of Israel.
Now read, skip down to verse 9.
Everybody ignores this number. Verse N,
read it. But after this I beheld in lo a
great multitude which no man could
number of all nations and kindred and
people and tongue stood before the
throne and before the lamb clothed with
white robes and psalms in their hands.
So now, not only was 144,000, these
people that uh were sealed, God sealed
these people so he wouldn't pour his
wrath pour his wrath out on them when he
started pouring his wrath out on the uh
uh beast and false prophet. And these
had to be the people in the immediate
area. But let's see who they were. Skip
right on down to uh
uh verse 13 and continue and 13-1 17.
And one of the elders answered, saying
unto me, what are these which are
raiding white robes, and which came they
said unto him, Sir, thou knowest? And he
said to me, These are they which came
out of great tribulation, and have
washed their robes, and made them white
in the blood of the lamb. Therefore they
these are they that came out of great
tribulation. They survived the great
tribulation. And he said wash the roses
in the blood of the lamb. That mean that
simply mean that these people have been
uh uh uh converted because the white
raignment only mean righteousness. But
this is let you know that these people
were still mortals. Keep reading.
Therefore are they before the throne of
God and serve him day and night in his
temple. And he that siteth on the throne
shall dwell among them. They shall
hunger no more neither thirst anymore.
Neither shall the sun light on them nor
any heat. For the lamb which is in the
midst of the throne shall feed them and
shall lead them unto living fountains of
water. And God shall wipe away all tears
from their eyes.
See? So when when the Lord come,
everybody will be he'll be among
everybody on earth, right?
And uh when they say going to lead and
guide them to living waters, that mean
that they are not immortal cuz they if
they was immortal, they wouldn't have to
be led to living waters because they
will already be immortal. But then this
is only quoting what Isaiah said. Let's
go into Isaiah 49 and read verses 9 and
10.
Read it when you get there. That thou
mayest say to the prisoner, go forth to
them that are
Isaiah what now? 49 did I say and verse
verse 9 and 10? Yeah.
Yeah. You want me to start at verse 8 or
Okay, start at verse eight. Thus sayeth
the Lord, in the acceptable time have I
heard thee. In the day of salvation have
I helped thee. And I will preserve thee
and will give thee for a covenant of the
people to establish the earth to cause
to inherit the desolate heritage that
thou mayest say. That's Jesus that he's
given he's talking to them or given for
a covenant of the people. Okay. That
they may do what? Go ahead. That thou
mayest say to the prisoners, go forth to
them that are in darkness. Show
yourselves. They shall feed in the waves
of their pastures, and shall be in all
high places. They shall not hunger, nor
thirst. Neither shall the heat nor sun
smite them. For he that have mercy on
them shall lead them. Even by the
springs of water shall he guide them.
And and Revelation called it, Revelation
7th chapter, they called it the uh uh uh
uh springs of living waters. So this is
what's going to happen. He's talking
about mortal people. Okay. Yeah.
They have not been saved. They are not
saved until you are
changed. That's right. And you're no
more mortals. You are immortals. That's
when you are saved. Not a day before.
That's all I have to say. All right.
Hope that answered your question there.
As we move on to our next question, next
one. The
domination station asks, "Can other
nations besides Israel prophesied of the
Lord?" Can other nations besides Israel
prophesy of the Lord? Prophesy, spread
the good news or let them know about
this Bible and what's going on, the
coming of the Lord and all that good
stuff. Sure, you could tell other other
nations can tell people that because the
Lord said that the gospel has to go out
throughout the whole world. Then shall
the end come. So hey, nothing wrong if
you got some word and you letting your
light shine and letting it be known
about the past, present, and future. But
let's go into Malachi 3 and 16. Malachi
3 and 16.
This word, hey, it need to be told. It
is a beautiful lifesaver. Malachi 3:16.
Go
ahead. Then they that feared the Lord
spake often one to another. And the Lord
hearkened and heard it, and a book of
remembrance was written before him, for
them that feared the Lord, and that
thought upon his name.
Yes. So that is uh hey, that is a good
thing to be able to do. Let people know
about the Lord when you got some wisdom
and some knowledge. Turn over to Joel
the 2 chapter. Joel
2. Joel 2. And let's pick it up at that
verse 28 and 29. And then we gonna go to
Acts 2 after that. And that'll be it. Go
ahead,
brother. Joel 2. Yeah. 28 and 29.
And it shall come to pass afterward that
I will pour out my spirit upon all
flesh, and your sons and your daughters
shall prophesize. Your old men shall
dream dreams. Your younger men shall see
visions, and also upon the servants, and
upon the handmmaids, in those days will
I pour out my spirit. So Lord is pouring
out his spirit, even a spirit of
salvation, to all those that have an ear
to hear. So yeah, all nations are
included in that. Spread that good word
if you got it because the end is truly
near. Now, let's pick up Joel in Acts
the second
chapter. Let's go to Acts two. When you
get there, pick it up at verse 16 for
me. Acts 2 and verse 16.
But this is that which was spoken by the
prophet Joel. So Joel spoke of that
black and old testament. We just read
it. Go ahead. And it shall come to pass
in the last days, say God, I will pour
out of my spirit upon all flesh, and
your sons and your daughters shall
prophesize, and your young men shall see
visions, and your old men shall dream
dreams. Yep. And on my servants, and on
my handmaids, I will pour out in those
days of my spirit, and they shall
prophesize. Yeah. So, hey, to be able to
prophesy and give some knowledge to
those that are lacking about this true
word of God. Hey, all nations are free
to join in on that as long as it's the
true word of God. That's all I got.
I want to add a couple of places. Yes,
sir.
All nations might be free, but are they
capable? Let's go into Romans the 3,
read verse one.
Romans 3 and1.
Read it. What advantage then have the
Jew? Or what profit is there of
circumcision?
Much in every way, chiefly because that
unto them were committed the oracles of
God. Yes.
Right.
Let's go to Romans the 9th chapter.
Start reading at verse
one. We're going to read down to verse
four.
Romans 9 and1. I say the truth in
Christ. I lie not. My conscience also
bear me witness in the Holy Ghost that I
have great heaviness and continual
sorrow in my heart. If I wish, if I
could wish that myself were a curse from
Christ, for my brethren, my kinsmen
according to the flesh, who are
Israelites, to whom pertainth the
adoption and the glory and the covenants
and the giving of the law and the
service of God and the promises.
So it look like Israel was given that
job. So brother nations going to do the
same thing. And they have they have to
make sure that they have been taught by
Israel because the Lord said he showed
his word to Israel and his stature to
Jacob and he have not done that with any
other nation. That's right. That's all.
Yes sir. Thank you for that add-on. That
definitely needed to be put in there.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. Next one. The mech king says, "Do
we boil or not boil the Passover lamb?"
Exodus 12 verse 9 says not to boil it.
While Deuteronomy 16:7 says to boil it.
All right, Brother Dre, what you say?
Let's go to uh ex Exodus 12 and read
verse 9. Do we boil the Passover lamb or
do we we don't do neither one of them
now? But let's
let's go to Exodus 12, read verse nine,
brother. Go ahead.
Eat not of it raw, nor Sodom at all with
water, but roast with fire, his head
with his legs, and with the puritans
thereof. So, it says, "Don't boil it at
all with water, but roast it with fire."
That's what it says here. Now, let's go
to um Deuteronomy 16 and read verse 7.
Deuteronomy 16 and verse 7. Go ahead.
And thou shalt roast and eat it in the
place which the Lord thy God shall
choose. and thou shalt turn it in the
morning and go to thy tents.
Okay, so both of these places tell you
to roast it when was roasting it, but we
don't do that. Now, let's go to 1
Corinthians 5 and we going to read
verses 7 and 8. 1 Corinthians
5 7 and
8. Go ahead, brother.
Purge out therefore the old leaven that
ye may be a new lamb as ye are
unleavened. For even Christ our Passover
is sacrificed for us. That's right.
Christ is our Passover lamb. And the
lamb that was being sacrificed at that
time was pointing to Christ being
Passover lamb. Go ahead brother. So
therefore, let us keep the feast, but
not with old leaven, neither with the
leaven of malice and wickedness, but
with the unleavened bread of sincerity
and truth. That's right. So now there
are those that are still doing this.
Let's go over to Exodus 12 and we going
to read verse 5. Exodus 12 and five.
When you get there, go ahead, brother.
There are those that are still roasting
the
lamb, but this is how they should do it
if they're going to do it. Go ahead.
Your lamb shall be without blemish. A
male of the first year. You shall take
it out from the sheep or from the goats.
So wait a minute. You cannot go to the
grocery store and buy a lamb cuz you
don't know if it's of the first year.
You don't know if it's without blemish.
You get a leg of lamb, you don't know if
it's male or
female. You doing wrong wrong wrong. You
not even doing wrong right. But Christ,
our Passover lamb has been sacrificed
for us. So I hope helps.
Yes, sir. Thank you for that, brother.
So all you do on Passover is eat the
bread and the wine and the wine.
Got it. All
right. Hope that that helped you as we
continue to move on with a time check.
The time is
8:39. Thou asks, "Does the Bible teach
that demons still cause sickness today?"
Like in Luke 13
11-16 and Matthew 17 14-18.
All right. So, Brother Julius, we
talking about demons here. What say you?
Do does the Bible teach that demon still
cause sickness today? H
uh let's look let's let's see what Luke
13 says, Tanzel. Luke 13 and read verse
11. Let's look at what it says.
And behold, there was a woman which had
a spirit of infirmity 18 years, and was
bowed together, and could in no wise
lift up herself.
Uh-huh. And when Jesus saw her, he
called her to him, and said unto her,
Woman, thou I lose for thy infirmity.
Now Jesus is healing a woman who was
bent over for 38 years on the Sabbath
day. Go ahead.
And he laid his hands on her. And
immediately she was made straight and
glorified God. Go ahead.
And the rulers of the synagogue answered
with indignation because that Jesus had
healed on the Sabbath day and said unto
the people, "There are six days which
men ought to work, and in them therefore
come and be healed, and not on the
Sabbath day." Skip down to verse 16. Go
ahead.
And ought not this woman being a
daughter of Abraham whom Satan had
bound, lo these 18 years be loosed from
this bond on the Sabbath day. How did
Jesus know that she was afflicted 38
years? Now let's uh the Bible does not
teach that demons still cause sickness
and day. Let's look at what the Bible
teaches. Let's go to Amos and you can
read the other scripture which is
similar.
Let's go to Amos the 3 chapter and let's
look at what the Bible
teaches. Amos chapter 3 and we're going
to read verse
6. Amos chapter 3 and verse 6. Go ahead.
Shall a trumpet be blown in the city and
the people not be afraid? Go ahead.
Shall there be evil in the city and the
Lord have not done it? And the Lord has
not done it or allowed it or permitted
it. Because angels are not rogue. They
are not rogue running around doing what
they want to do. They operate by
permission or commandment. Let me give
you a perfect example of angels
operating by permission or commandment.
Job chapter one. The Bible teaches that
the angels operate by permission and or
commandment. Job chapter one.
And let's look who had to ask God for
permission to mess with
Job. Job 1:10. Go ahead,
brother. Has not thou made in heads
about him and about his house and about
all that have on every side? Thou hast
blessed the work of his hands and his
substance is increasing the land. So the
devil know what's going on because he
walk around. Go ahead. But put forth thy
hand now and touch all things. for thy
hand. Did he say I'm I'mma do this on my
own? He said, "Put forth thine hand now.
Shall there be evil in the city and I
the Lord have not done it?" Go ahead.
And all that he have, and he will curse
thee to thy face. Now look what the Lord
said to Satan. Satan put in request in.
And now look what Satan The Lord said to
Satan. Go ahead. The Lord said unto
Satan, "Behold, all that he have is in
thy power. Only upon himself put not
forth thy hand."
So, Satan went forth from the presence
of the Lord. So, Satan went forth to go
ahead and afflict Job. Job chapter 2
real quick. And this is it. Job 2 and
verse uh uh uh man, you can read the
whole thing, but read verse four cuz he
asked them
uh again another question. Do Satan
serve you for do Job serve you for
nothing? But now verse four, go ahead.
And Satan answered the Lord and said,
"Skin for skin. Yeah, all that a man
have would he give for his life?" How he
How do he know? Cuz you know, put man to
the test. Go ahead.
But put forth thy hand now and touch his
bones and his flesh, and he will curse
thee to thy face. Now put forth your
hand,
Lord, and he'll curse you. Now look at
verse six. Go ahead. And the Lord said
unto Satan, "Behold, he is in thy hand,
but save his life."
Hey, he in your hand, but don't kill
him. Go ahead.
So when Satan forth from the presence of
the Lord smoke Joel with sore boils from
the sole of his foot unto his crown. So
now there's your answer. The Bible
teaches that these angels work by
permission or commandment. They can't do
nothing without permission or
commandment from the Lord. I hope that
helped.
Yes, sir. Brother Julius, power belongth
unto God. May the Lord said he afflicted
Egyp Egypt by sending evil angels among
them, didn't he? That's right. That's
right. And then the Lord tell you, I
will take away the diseases from you. He
put the diseases on you and he going to
add Revelation 22. He said, I'mma add
the things, the plagues that are not
written this book. So these demon do not
work on their own. They work by
permission or commandment. Right. Yeah.
That's great power what we speaking
about. All right. Hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
question, sister. As time is ticking.
Yes. Philosophy asks, "Is Genesis
3:E15 the first prophecy of Jesus?"
Let's go to Genesis 3 and 15 asking, "Is
this the first prophecy of Jesus?" And
caller would take it from there.
Genesis 3 and
15. And I will put enmity between thee
and the woman, and between thy seed and
her seed, and it shall bruise thy head,
and thou shall bruise his
heel. No, that's not the first
prophecy. Go to Genesis 2 and read 17.
But of the tree of the knowledge of good
and evil, thou shall not eat of it. For
in the day that thou eatest thereof,
thou shalt surely die.
That is the first prophecy. Yes, sir. If
you eat it, I'm telling you now, if you
eat of the tree of the knowledge of good
and evil, you going to
die. Adam ate it, ate of the tree of the
knowledge of good and evil, and we are
dying to this day. That was the first
prophecy.
All right. Okay. Thank you for Thank you
for that light and I hope you saw it as
we continue to move on from our next to
our Yes. N Yes. Nissi Jones asks, "Does
the tribulation begin with the opening
of the first four seals or would that be
the beginning of sorrow that the Bible
talks about?"
Jerome, shed a little light here on this
uh opening of the first four seals.
Um let's let's go to Revelations chapter
6. Revelations chapter 6. Yeah.
Pick it up at verse uh one. Read it to
the four.
And I saw when the lamb opened one of
the seals, and I heard it heard it as it
was the noise of thunder. And one of the
four beasts, saying, Come and see. And I
saw, and behold, a white horse, and he
that sat on, and it had a bow, a bow,
and a crown was given unto him. And he
went forth conquering, and to conquer.
And when he had opened the second seal,
I heard the second beast said, "Come and
see." And there went out another horse
that was red, and power was given to him
that set there on to take peace from the
earth, and that they should kill one
another, and there was given unto him a
great sword.
Yeah.
See these seal seals here. The first one
is the beginning of the great
tribulation.
Okay, the sorrows is happening in our
time right now, right? You know, but uh
the great tribulation start right here.
So, let's tie with
uh Daniel's 11 and 31 and then we going
to go to Matthews after that.
Tanzel. And this is the uh this this guy
on this white horse. He the abomination
of desolation. We about to read about in
Daniel's the 11th chapter verse 31. And
in Matthews, we going to go there after
this. Go ahead. Uh Daniel 11 and
31. And arms shall stand on his part.
They shall pollute the sanctuary of
strength, and shall take away the daily
sacrifice, and they shall place the
abomination that make it
desolate. And such as do wickedly
against the covenant shall he corrupt by
flatteries. But the people that do know
their God shall be strong and do
exploits. Okay? And so the abomination
of desolation
uh spoken of in that verse, that's the
same one that was sitting on that white
horse in Revelations the 6th chapter
verse two. And he going to
bring he going to earth you in this
great tribulation. Okay. So uh let's go
to that um Matthews
24 quickly. Matthews
24, read verse 15 and 16. Then we going
to skip.
When ye therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the prophet, stand in the holy
place. Who so read, let him
understand. Then let them which be in
Judea flee into the mountains.
Uh-huh. Now skip down to verse 21. Read
the 22.
For then shall be great tribulation,
such as was not since the beginning of
the world to this time, no nor ever
shall be. And except those days should
be shortened, there shall no flesh be
saved, but for the elect's sake, those
days shall be shortened. That's it.
That's all I got on.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next as we are ticking. Go ahead.
Next one. Tina Ray says, "I believe in
Jesus, God, the Holy Spirit, but is it
wrong to not want to be called a
Christian? I'm reading the book of
Exodus, but hasn't finished." And God
called the people of Israel, his people.
Wasn't Jesus a descendant from Judah?
Does that make him Jewish? or does he
have to to follow Judaism to be called
Jewish? And why are followers of a
Jewish man calling themselves
Christians?
All right, it's a lot in that question,
brother Julius, but uh please shed some
light.
It is your prerogative if you want to be
or want to or or does not want to be
called a Christian. Me myself, I call it
an honor. It is an honor to be called a
Christian, which means a follower of
Jesus Christ. And I'm not ashamed of
that. I'm not saying not saying that you
are, but I'm not ashamed of that. It is
an honor. Jesus told you in St. John
14:15, if you love me, keep my
commandments. Let's go to Acts and let's
look at what the disciples did. Acts the
11th
chapter.
Acts the 11th chapter 10 just verse 26
look what Jesus disciples were
called and they are going to be judges
in the kingdom of
Jesus. Acts 11-26 where you get it. Read
it. And when he had found them he
brought him unto Antioch. And it came to
pass that a whole year they assembled
themselves with the church and taught
much people. And the disciples were
called Christians first in Antioch.
So a Christian is one who follows and
obeys the teachings and sayings of Jesus
Christ. Now uh it is an honor to be
called a Christian. You keep the
commandments. You love him. You show you
love him and you do what he say. So now
your other part of your question is uh
uh Jesus was called a Jew. He was a Jew.
Uh I ain't see I don't see nowhere in
the Bible where Jesus is called Jewish.
A Jew is one from the tribe of Judah,
Jacob's fourth son. So uh we as
Christians is a title. It is a title and
it is a way of life. So therefore we are
Israelite Hebrew Israelites of the tribe
of Jacob uh with this his descendants.
We are the original Christians. So we
are not afraid to be called Christians,
but we follow Jesus. It's just that he
came out of the tribe of Judah, Jacob
for son, a lineage. A lineage. And I
might be a Jew. I might be one of the
sons of uh Jacob, but I would not be
ashamed to be called a Christian or I
would not. God give me the right mind
and I won't I I have I accept that
title. That's all I got. Anybody else
want to add?
Can I can I just let's go to first Peter
the 4th chapter and read verses 14- 16.
1 Peter 4 vers 14- 16. Read it when you
get it. Tanzel.
If ye be reproached for the name of
Christ, happy are ye for the spirit of
glory and of God receiveth upon you on
their part. He is evil spoken of. But on
your part, he is glorified.
But let none suffer as a murderer or as
a thief or as a evildoer or as a busy
body in other men's
matters. But yet if any man suffer as a
Christian, let him not be ashamed. But
let him glorify God on this behalf.
That's right. If you suffer as a
Christian, That's right. glorify God on
his behalf.
That's all I got. Thank you, brother.
All right, let me throw in
uh let's go to Matthew the 19th chapter
and show you where uh what the uh
somebody where Peter asked the Lord what
will they get,
you know, and he told them that they'll
be sitting on throne.
Yeah. All right. That would be um verse
pick it up at 27 19 and 27. Give
scripture Cordel give scripture please
again. Give verse Matthew Matthew 19 and
27.
Thank you.
Yes sir. Then answered Peter and said
unto him, Behold, we have forsaken all
and follow thee. What shall we have?
Therefore, Jesus answered unto them, But
verily I say unto you, that ye which
have followed me in the regeneration,
when the Son of Man shall sit in the
throne of his glory, you shall also
shall sit upon 12 thrones, judging the
12 tribes of
Israel, and every one that have
forsaken.
Now these
12 were called Christian and they didn't
kick against it.
They going to sit during the millennium
period, they going to sit on 12 throne
judging the 12 tribes of Israel.
So the people that refuse to be called
Christian, what did the God What did
Jesus promise
you? Food for thought. That's all I have
to say. Mhm. All right. I'd like to
thank my fellow Christian brothers for
some good answers there as we move on to
our next one. Moving on. Z Amaru Israel
says, "I understand that tongues mean
language, but please explain its context
in Acts
19:E6 and Mark 16:E1 17." All right.
Dealing with speaking in tongues. Why
don't we go there and then let's open
that up to the panel. Acts
19 and sister Deborah, what was the
question again?
Uh they want you to explain the context
for Acts 19 verse 6 and Mark 16 verse1
17.
Okay. All right. Why don't you go right
ahead and read that, brother? and then
we're going to open it up to the panel.
And when Paul had laid his hands upon
them, the Holy Ghost came on them and
they spake with tongues and prophesied.
A little explanation from the panel on
that.
Now read other script other place. Oh,
you want 16 verse 17.
And these signs shall follow them that
believe. In my name shall they cast out
devils. They shall speak with new
tongues. Now, now that have two
different meaning there. One of them
there is a reaction where people start
speaking uh uh in another
language and it could be generated by
the Holy Spirit. But this last one where
it's talking about you begin to speak
with a new tongue. That mean that your
conversation is going to change. But
let's go. What is that? The tongue
chapter. What's it first Corinthians?
What's the 11th chapter? 14. Or is it
the 14th? Huh? 14. 14. Yes. Start at
verse one.
Follow after charity and desire
spiritual gift, but rather that ye may
prophesy. For he that speaketh in
unknown,
go ahead. For he that speaketh in an
unknown tongue speaketh not unto men,
but unto God, but no man understandeth
him, how be it in the spirit he speaketh
of mysteries.
Now that lets you know that the Lord can
the Lord the spirit can come upon you
and you can speak in an unknown tongue.
If you keep reading it, tell you but do
it in order. And if you and if uh you
speak in an unknown tongue, let there be
an interpreter. So it's still another
language. I want you to skip down where
Paul said be where he say uh uh uh in
the law it is uh it is uh uh where he
said be you say in the word be in malice
be children but in in the word be uh uh
uh men that same chapter
that uh verse 20
start let me see what it is yeah verse
20 19 and then 20 19. Yes, sir. Dre.
Yeah. In the church, I have rather speak
five words with my understanding, that
by my voice I might teach others also,
then 10,000 words in an unknown tongue.
But brother, be not children in
understanding. How be it, in malice be
ye children, but in understanding be
men. In the law it is written, with men
of other tongues and other lips will I
speak unto this people. And yet for all
that will they not hear me, said the
Lord God.
And that's what the Lord meant. So he
said this people, he's talking about
Israel. He going to speak, why would he
say with men of other tongues? He
quoting Isaiah because he going to
scatter Israel all over the globe. And
whatever language that they speak,
that's the language he gonna speak to
them in. Right? But then that's starting
out to get people's attention. But I
want you to see who tongues are for.
Keep reading. They tell you what tongues
are for. Who?
Well, for tongues are for a sign, not to
them that believe, but to them that
believe not.
But prophesying serveth not for them
that believe not but for them which
believe.
See tongues are for non-believers. God
was starting this thing off. He came and
he started doing something new. They
wanted to get these people attention.
They baptizing people that would happen.
Laying hands on people that would
happen. But now if you a believer you
don't need a sign. The sign is the
tongues are for nonbelievers.
The churches have lied saying if you
don't speak in tongues you ain't got the
Holy Ghost. That is the biggest lie
told. Not one of the prophets spoke in
tongues. But the Lord told you that they
spoke by the spirit of God. All of them
spoke that they was moved by the Holy
Ghost. But they spoke in their own
language. Yeah. I'm not saying that God
bring a reaction on it because he did.
And people speak in some unknown tongue
and they don't know what they said. Just
like Paul said, you speaking to
God. But tongues are not the a
prerequisite for being holy or being a
servant. Tongues are for
nonbelievers. If you believe in God,
don't have to have to do no miracle or
speaking unknown tongue. That's all I
have to say.
All right, that was a good question. Go
ahead, Deborah. Yes. Uh, brother
Cornell, let's answer this last
question. You should be able to answer
it very quickly. Uh, what they're
stating. Uh, this last question is from
Malik Shakur and he asks, "Is there any
explanation to why I keep seeing the
number 666 everywhere? It can be on back
license plates at work on boxes. I even
heard someone ask for a lottery ticket
and said, "Give me three sixes." So, is
there an explanation that he's saying
666 everywhere?
Coincidence.
And there it is. Coincident.
Yep.
So, time check, sister. The time is
9:04.
All right. We'd like to thank everybody
from all around the world who tuned in
with us and sent in your questions. We
took joy in answering them. And we want
to say that if you submitted a question,
we didn't get to it. Please don't
resubmit it. Sister Deborah, take it,
put it in rotation, and we will deal
with that question next week. So we want
to say that we thank you again and until
we all come together again, please be
safe, be blessed, stay prayed up, and
may the Lord have mercy on us all as our
brother Tanzel closes us out.
Our Father, which are in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread. And forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debtors. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen. Amen. Amen. Amen.
Good night all. The night.